Joel Oppenheimer Papers 1990.0056
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series II: Poetry, undated, 1953-1987
  - Subseries A: Individual Poems, undated
    - Foster Mother ( Collected Later Poems) (includes 1987 news clipping of source story) (Box 12:603)
    - Fragment from the Works of Anacreon ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 12:604)
    - Free Country, ca. 1972-1974 (Box 12:605)
    - Friend ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 12:606)
    - Fugue, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 12:607)
    - F Y I ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 12:608)
    - Game, ca. 1960 (Box 12:609)
    - Garden ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 12:610)
    - Gardener ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 12:611)
    - Getting There ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 12:612)
    - Ghost Lover (includes variant TSS, w/ corrections), ca. 1983 (Box 12:613)
    - Ghosts (includes variant TSS, "Drunks", "For a Friend"), 1975 (Box 12:614)
    - Ghosts ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1985-1987 (Box 12:615)
    - Gift ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 12:616)
    - God ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 12:617)
    - God Knows, ca. 1960-1962 (Box 12:618)
    - Gone Fishing, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 12:619)
    - Grace ( On Occasion) (includes variant TSS, "Grace Before Dinner"), 1960-1970 (Box 12:620)
    - Grace ("for Thanksgiving 1963") ( On Occasion) (Box 12:621)
    - Grace ("Thanksgiving 1973") (Box 12:622)
    - Grace ( News, Dates, and Places) (includes variant TSS, "Thanksgiving Grace"), ca. 1975-1978 (Box 12:623)
    - Grace Before Breakfast, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 12:624)
    - Grace for Painters ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1961 (Box 12:625)
    - Grace for Thanksgiving ("11/22/62") ( On Occasion) (includes MSS version), 1962 (Box 12:626)
    - Grace for Thanksgiving, 1971 (Box 12:627)
    - Granite ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1985-1987 (Box 12:628)
    - Grant Us ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:629)
    - Great American Novel ( In Time), 1965 (Box 12:630)
    - Great Clod, ca. 1958-1964 (Box 12:631)
    - Greenery, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 12:632)
    - Grown Alba ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 12:633)
    - Gryllidae Achene ( New Hampshire Journal) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 12:634)
    - Haggadah: A Telling, ca. 1957-1960 (Box 12:635)
    - Hah-hah ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:636)
    - Haiku ("Joy! One Happy Nexus..."), 1979 (Box 12:637)
    - Haiku in Double Time, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:638)
    - Hair of the Friend (includes variant TSS), 1972-1976 (Box 12:639)
    - Happy New Year ( On Occasion), ca. 1964 (Box 12:640)
    - Hardboiled Mystery ( New Spaces) (includes variant, longer TSS, "Poem for Dashiell Hammett..."), 1975-1983 (Box 12:641)
    - Harvest Moon ( On Occasion) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1968-1970 (Box 12:642)
    - Having Learned, ca. 1960? (Box 12:643)
    - Heart ( In Time), 1958 (Box 12:644)
    - Heart Full Of ( The Love Bit), ca. 1958-1962 (Box 12:645)
    - Hello There ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 12:646)
    - Heroes in the Shape of Monstrosities, 1956 (Box 12:647)
    - Herself Wrenched Out of Herself (includes variant TSS), ca. 1955-1960 (Box 12:648)
    - Her Son the Star, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:649)
    - Hike You, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:650)
    - Historical Notes (signed as "sol d siple"), ca. 1976-1982 (Box 12:651)
    - History, ca. 1953 (Box 12:652)
    - Hokku 237B ( On Occasion), 1960 (Box 12:653)
    - Hold That Line, ca. 1957-1960 (Box 12:654)
    - Homage to Nicanor Parra ( On Occasion), ca. 1970 (Box 12:655)
    - Homeless, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 12:656)
    - Home Thoughts ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:657)
    - Houses ( New Spaces) (w/ first draft MSS), 1975-1983 (Box 12:658)
    - How Bad it Gets, ca. 1957-1962 (Box 12:659)
    - How the Pomegranate Proved Useless, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 12:660)
    - How to Approach Black Art ( On Occasion), 1971 (Box 12:661)
    - Hunter ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 12:662)
    - Hunters, ca. 1964-1967 (Box 12:663)
    - Hurricane ( Collected Later Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1986 (Box 12:664)
    - Husband, 1960-1962 (Box 12:665)
    - Husband ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:666)
    - Hyacinthus ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:667)
    - Hymn, ca. 1953-1959 (Box 12:668)
    - I Can't Call My Momma Any More, ca. 1972-1978 (Box 12:669)
    - If I'm Allowed, 1963 (Box 12:670)
    - If There was Sense ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca, 1972-1976 (Box 12:671)
    - I Have Let My Hair Grow Long, ca. 1962-1966 (Box 12:672)
    - Iliad ( On Occasion), 1958 (Box 12:673)
    - Immediate Present, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:674)
    - In Answer ("to someone's plea for 170 syllables"), ca. 1960-1964 (Box 12:675)
    - Incantation ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1984 (Box 12:676)
    - In Mind, In Body ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 12:677)
    - In New Hampshire ( New Hampshire Journal) (includes variant TSS, "The Earth Moved Today"), 1983 (Box 12:678)
    - Innocent Breasts ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:679)
    - Inscribed in a Book Offered at Auction, 1975 (Box 12:680)
    - In Springtime ("for m.f."), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 12:681)
    - In the Beginning ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 12:682)
    - In the Cards, ca. 1964 (Box 12:683)
    - In the Clutch, ca. 1958-1961 (Box 12:684)
    - In the Morning ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 12:685)
    - In the Science Museum, ca. 1985 (Box 12:686)
    - Issue at Hand ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 12:687)
    - I Surrender Dear, ca. 1971-1980 (Box 12:688)
    - It Ain/t News ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 12:689)
    - I Think I Need a Drink ( In Time), 1964 (Box 12:690)
    - It is a Sign of Spring, ca. 1958-1964 (Box 12:691)
    - Ivoe, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 12:692)
    - I Was Not Sick, Just Dissatisfied, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 12:693)
    - Jane Street Poems, ca. 1982 (Box 12:694)
    - Jewish Poem, ca. 1961-1966 (Box 12:695)
    - Joe Flaherty ( Collected Later Poems), 1983 (Box 12:696)
    - Joel L. Oppenheimer Memorial Garden ( On Occasion), ca. 1970 (Box 12:697)
    - Just One More Time, ca. 1957-1960 (Box 12:698)
    - Kaddish, ca. 1960-1965 (Box 12:699)
    - Kopf that Cheers ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 12:700)
    - Ladies of Westbeth ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 12:701)
    - Lady ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 12:702)
    - Lady Across ( On Occasion), 1968-1971 (Box 12:703)
    - Lady of Madness ( The Woman Poems) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 12:704)
    - Laertes Speaks ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS and MSS notes), ca. 1985-1987 (Box 12:705)
    - La Huelga ( On Occasion), ca. 1970 (Box 12:706)
    - Landscape ( Collected Later Poems) (TSS carries title "Autumn Landscape - Rochester"), ca. 1983-85 (Box 12:707)
    - La Revolucion ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 12:708)
    - Late Winter Poem ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:709)
    - Leave it to Me Blues ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 12:710)
    - Legend ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:711)
    - Leo Oppenheimer ( On Occasion), 1969 (Box 12:712)
    - Lesbian Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 12:713)
    - Lesson, 1963 (Box 12:714)
    - Lesson ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:715)
    - Lesson ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 12:716)
    - Lesson I ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 12:717)
    - Lessons I ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:718)
    - Lessons II ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:719)
    - Life Studies ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 12:720)
    - Let Me Go Home Whiskey ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:721)
    - Letter to Irving Layton, ca. 1958 (Box 12:722)
    - Letter to Philip ( Names, Dates, and Places) (includes variant TSS, "A Letter to Philip Whalen on His Becoming a Zen Student"), ca. 1973 (Box 12:723)
    - Letters for M C ( Collected Later Poems), 1986 (Box 12:724)
    - Lie Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 12:725)
    - Life ( In Time), ca. 1962-1966 (Box 12:726)
    - Life, ca. 1975-1980 (Box 12:727)
    - Life as it is Lived ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:728)
    - Life Savers, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 12:729)
    - Like a, ca. 1958-1964 (Box 12:730)
    - Lilies and Roses all Sorts of, ca. 1958-1964 (Box 12:731)
    - Li Po and the Lilies, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 12:732)
    - Little Boys Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS variant), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 12:733)
    - Little Mayan Head ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 12:734)
    - Long Blues ( Collected Later Poems) (variant TSS, preliminary version), ca. 1984-1987 (Box 12:735)
    - Long Distance, ca. 1970-1980 (Box 12:736)
    - Long Story, ca. 1962-1970 (Box 12:737)
    - Long Testament ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 12:738)
    - Long Way ( In Time) (Includes variant TSS), 1962-1968 (Box 12:739)
    - Lordy, Lordy (Includes variant TSS, MSS versions), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 12:740)
    - Love Bit ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 12:741)
    - Love Poem ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 12:742)
    - Love Poem ("for carlos and gerry"), ca. 1976-1980 (Box 12:743)
    - Lovesong ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 12:744)
    - Love's Other Side, ca. 1971-1976 (Box 12:745)
    - Loving Machine ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 12:746)
    - MacDonald's Arches: A Plot, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:747)
    - Magazine ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:748)
    - Magick, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 13:749)
    - Making a Valentine ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:750)
    - Man and Boy ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:751)
    - Man Discovered Through the Kitchen Window ( New Spaces), ca. 1975 (Box 13:752)
    - Map of the Island of Puerto Rico ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:753)
    - Mare Nostrum ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:754)
    - Marriage ("28 may 1967, for lewis and anne") ( On Occasion) (Box 13:755)
    - Mathematics ( In Time) (includes TSS variant), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 13:756)
    - May Day in the Park ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 13:757)
    - Mea Culpa ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:758)
    - Meat Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:759)
    - Medgar Evers, ca. 1963 (Box 13:760)
    - Meditations ( New Spaces), 1975 (Box 13:761)
    - Memo, ca. 1956-1960 (Box 13:762)
    - Memories of the Last of the Hot Young Men, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 13:763)
    - Merrily We Row Along, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:764)
    - Method for Suppplementarily Tracking Tornadoes... (includes source news clipping), 1976 (Box 13:765)
    - Mid-Passage ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:766)
    - Migrant Workers ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 13:767)
    - Mind, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 13:768)
    - Mind is the Easy Way Out ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 13:769)
    - Mineralogy 101 ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:770)
    - Mirror Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:771)
    - Mis Quote from Burns, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 13:772)
    - Mister Intelligence ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:773)
    - Modern Times ( In Time) (includes TSS variant, "In Our Times"), 1962-1968 (Box 13:774)
    - Monosyllable Poem ( The Woman Poems) (variant TSS), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:775)
    - Moratorium ( On Occasion), 1969 (Box 13:776)
    - Morning, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 13:777)
    - Morning Song ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:778)
    - Mother Loose, ca. 1973-1983 (Box 13:779)
    - Mother Poem ( The Woman Poems) (Includes variant TSS), ca. 1974 (Box 13:780)
    - Mother Prayer ( The Woman Poems) (TSS variant, "In Memory of Rod Rademacher) (with clipping), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:781)
    - Mother Prayer ( The Woman Poems) (TSS carries title, "This Child"), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:782)
    - Moving Out ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:783)
    - Murder, ca. 1958-1964 (Box 13:784)
    - Muse Poem ( The Woman Poems) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1974 (Box 13:785)
    - My Blue Heaven ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:786)
    - My Oldest Son ( On Occasion) (TSS titled, "The Oldest Son"), 1960-1970 (Box 13:787)
    - My Sons, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 13:788)
    - Mythology ( In Time), 1964 (Box 13:789)
    - Mythos, ca. 1971-1975 (Box 13:790)
    - Naked Poem ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:791)
    - Naked Poem II ( The Woman Poems) (TSS not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:792)
    - Napalm Poem ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 13:793)
    - Nathaniel's Grace, 1974 (Box 13:794)
    - Nathaniel's Valentine ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 13:795)
    - Nature Boy ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:796)
    - N. B. ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:797)
    - New Basket, ca. 1960-1962 (Box 13:798)
    - New Blues for the Moon ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), ca. 1960-1962 (Box 13:799)
    - New, Fiercer Look, ca. 1955-1958 (Box 13:800)
    - New Line ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 13:801)
    - New Nightgown ( In Time), 1964 (Box 13:802)
    - New Place in Town ( On Occasion) (includes variant TSS, "A New House"), 1963 (Box 13:803)
    - News ( On Occasion), ca. 1968-1971 (Box 13:804)
    - New Standard Simplified American Cabala for Home Use ( In Time), 1964 (Box 13:805)
    - New Year ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1973 (Box 13:806)
    - Night Air Becomes Noisome ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:807)
    - Night and Day ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 13:808)
    - Night Piece for Barbara, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 13:809)
    - Night Piece for Diana, 1964 (Box 13:810)
    - Nine to Five ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 13:811)
    - Nobody Ever Said It, ca. 1962-1968 (Box 13:812)
    - No Ifs, Ands, or Buts ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:813)
    - No Room at the Inn, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 13:814)
    - North: Studies, ca. 1978 (Box 13:815)
    - North: Summer, 1962-1968 (Box 13:816)
    - North: The Mother, ca. 1978 (Box 13:817)
    - Note ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:818)
    - Note for the Community Bulletin Board ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 13:819)
    - Notes for Poems for Summer, ca. 1976-1980 (Box 13:820)
    - Notes for the Holiday, ca. 1960-1964 (Box 13:821)
    - Notes Towards Lessons to Be Learned at Thirty ( In Time), ca. 1960 (Box 13:822)
    - Not Needed (poem cut from Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1971-1977 (Box 13:823)
    - Not Quite Half a Sonnet ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:824)
    - Nude Portrait (4 TSS Variants, same title), ca. 1959-1962 (Box 13:825)
    - Numbers ( The Dutiful Son), ca. 1959-1962 (Box 13:826)
    - Obituary ( On Occasion), ca. 1971 (Box 13:827)
    - Obscene Graces ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:828)
    - October 10, ca. 1972-1975 (Box 13:829)
    - October - Clouds, ca. 1973-1976 (Box 13:830)
    - Ode to a Study at Last ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 13:831)
    - Okay ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:832)
    - Older Man Thinking of Kore ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 13:833)
    - Old Hannah (song lyrics by Doc Reese?), ca. 1959-1960 (Box 13:834)
    - Old Man Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:835)
    - Old Song, 1956-1960 (Box 13:836)
    - Old Story ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:837)
    - On a Mezuzah ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:838)
    - On a New Anthology, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:839)
    - On a Tureen of Matzo-Ball Soup Given for Rosh Hashonah, ca. 1971-1974 (Box 13:840)
    - On Cardboard, 1974 (Box 13:841)
    - One Day at a Time ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 13:842)
    - Only Anarchist General ( On Occasion) (includes MSS copy), 1971 (Box 13:843)
    - Only Lester Hamp Poem ( Collected Later Poems) (TSS has title, "The First Lester Hamp Poem"; includes MSS note signed by Lester Hamp), ca. 1984 (Box 13:844)
    - On Parade ( The Love Bit), ca. 1958 (Box 13:845)
    - On the Giving of the Tallis (published as "Ritual" in Generations), 1979 (Box 13:846)
    - Orpheus ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers) (includes TSS fragment with same title), 1959-1962 (Box 13:847)
    - Ought to Know Better, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 13:848)
    - Paean, Prematurely for the Phillipines ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1985-1987 (Box 13:849)
    - Paranoia Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:850)
    - Paranoid Dream, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 13:851)
    - Passing the Time Away ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:852)
    - Pat and Mike ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:853)
    - Peaches ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 13:854)
    - Peire Vidal at Thirty-Two, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 13:855)
    - People are Starving in Europe ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 13:856)
    - Perfections ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 13:857)
    - Peter's Suite ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1985 (Box 13:858)
    - Piece Goods ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:859)
    - Pin the Tail on the Donkey ( On Occasion), ca. 1970? (Box 13:860)
    - Plan ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:861)
    - Plant, -- The Con, ca. 1966-1970 (Box 13:862)
    - Plus Ca Change ( Why Not)(includes TSS variant), ca. 1983-1984 (Box 13:863)
    - Poem ("31 December 1976"), 1976-1977 (Box 13:864)
    - Poem ("lady come on like"), ca. 1958-1966 (Box 13:865)
    - Poem ("listen: ") ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 13:866)
    - Poem ("they have returned") ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:867)
    - Poem for Bonnie or Clyde (Parts I-IV) ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:868)
    - Poem Based on Stasis ( Collected Later Poems) (includes variant TSS), 1985 (Box 13:869)
    - Poem in Tune with its Time ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:870)
    - Poem for Alfred and Constance (includes variant TSS, "Once More into the Breach"), ca. 1975 (Box 13:871)
    - Poem for Children ( On Occasion), ca. 1970 (Box 13:872)
    - Poem for Loud Laughter ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1960 (Box 13:873)
    - Poem for New Children ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1961 (Box 13:874)
    - Poem for Soho ( On Occasion), 1970 (Box 13:875)
    - Poem for Sugar Ray and the Girl Washing My Tub, ca. 1962-1970 (Box 13:876)
    - Poem for Theresa, ca. 1985-1987 (Box 13:877)
    - Poem for the New Year ( Names, Dates, and Places), 1973 (Box 13:878)
    - Poem for the New Year, 1978 (Box 13:879)
    - Poem for the State ( On Occasion), ca. 1968-1971 (Box 13:880)
    - Poem for Westbeth ("16 December 1970") ( On Occasion) (Box 13:881)
    - Poem for Westbeth ("26 May 1970) ( On Occasion) (Box 13:882)
    - Poem in Praise of Perseverance ( In Time), ca. 1963 (Box 13:883)
    - Poem on the Death of W C W 3 / 4 / 63 ( In Time), 1963 (Box 13:884)
    - Poems Don't Help, ca. 1956-1960 (Box 13:885)
    - Poem Written in and for New York City ( On Occasion), ca. 1965-1970 (Box 13:886)
    - Poem Written in the Light of Certain Events April 14, 1967 ( In Time) (Box 13:887)
    - Polish Cavalry ( On Occasion), 1970 (Box 13:888)
    - Porto Rican ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 13:889)
    - Postcard ( The Love Bit), 1958 (Box 13:890)
    - Postcard 37 ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 13:891)
    - Prayer ("for a wedding 11/29/63") ( On Occasion), 1963 (Box 13:892)
    - Prayer ("oh, the word, and the"), ca. 1960-1970 (Box 13:893)
    - Prayer Poem ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:894)
    - Preface ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:895)
    - Preliminaries: How to Take a Walk, ca. 1966-1970 (Box 13:896)
    - Presence, 1964 (Box 13:897)
    - Present ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:898)
    - President Nixon's Thanksgiving Day Poem, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:899)
    - Pride ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 13:900)
    - Progression Begins (also published as "The Progression" in New Spaces), ca. 1981 (Box 13:901)
    - Progress Report ( On Occasion), 1960-1970 (Box 13:902)
    - Proposal, ca. 1962-1966 (Box 13:903)
    - Prospectus, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 13:904)
    - Provence ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 13:905)
    - Psalm ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1961 (Box 13:906)
    - Public Affairs ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:907)
    - Pure in Heart ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 13:908)
    - Purple Blue in the ( The Love Bit), 1958 (Box 13:909)
    - Purple Flowers ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:910)
    - Q E D, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 13:911)
    - Quadrivia ( Just Friends/ Friends and Lovers), 1959-1962 (Box 13:912)
    - Quasi-Formal Piece, ca. 1964-1966 (Box 13:913)
    - Quatrain ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 13:914)
    - Question, ca. 1962-1966 (Box 13:915)
    - Question Poem ( The Woman Poems) (Variant TSS, not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:916)
    - Questions, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:917)
    - Questions for the Mother ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:918)
    - Quiet Blues ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 13:919)
    - Racial Memory ( In Time), 1964 (Box 13:920)
    - Rage and, ca. 1956-1960 (Box 13:921)
    - Rain ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 13:922)
    - Ralph ( On Occasion), 1967 (Box 13:923)
    - Raw Taste of, ca. 1960-1966 (Box 13:924)
    - Reading In, ca. 1966-1970 (Box 13:925)
    - Recapitulation, ca. 1955? (Box 13:926)
    - Recipe ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:927)
    - Red Star over China ( On Occasion), ca. 1966-1971 (Box 13:928)
    - Reflection Ten to Fifteen Years After, ca. 1958? (Box 13:929)
    - Renewal ( The Dutiful Son), 1955 (Box 13:930)
    - Re-Organization ( Names, Dates, and Places) (includes variant TSS and variant MSS), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:931)
    - Riddle ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:932)
    - Rock and the Hard Place ( New Spaces), 1975-1983 (Box 13:933)
    - Romance is a Eulogy for the Dead Past ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:934)
    - Root GN ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1985-1987 (Box 13:935)
    - Round ( Collected Later Poems), ca. 1984 (Box 13:936)
    - Rule ("for bruce and roxanne") ( On Occasion), 1965 (Box 13:937)
    - Running it Down, ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:938)
    - Sad Song, ca. 1970 (Box 13:939)
    - Safe at Home Blues, ca. 1957-1962 (Box 13:940)
    - Scene ( The Love Bit), 1957 (Box 13:941)
    - Schizophrenia ( New Spaces) (Includes variant TSS), ca. 1975-1983 (Box 13:942)
    - Screaming Poem ( The Woman Poems) (variant TSS, not titled), ca. 1973-1975 (Box 13:943)
    - Sea Poem ( In Time), ca. 1958 (Box 13:944)
    - Season Poem I ( The Woman Poems) (includes variant untitled TSS), ca. 1974 (Box 13:945)
    - Season Poem II ( The Woman Poems), ca. 1974 (Box 13:946)
    - Second Song at Saint Andrews ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 13:947)
    - Section: Settlement, 1977 (Box 13:948)
    - Seize the Day ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:949)
    - Self-Pity Blues, ca. 1974 (Box 13:950)
    - Serving Notice ( Names, Dates, and Places) (includes variant TSS), ca. 1972-1976 (Box 13:951)
    - Shooting the Moon ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:952)
    - Short Blues ( The Love Bit), 1957-1962 (Box 13:953)
    - Short Grace, ca. 1958-1966 (Box 13:954)
    - Sioux Song ( Names, Dates, and Places), ca. 1972-1978 (Box 13:955)
    - Sirventes Against Waiting ( In Time) (includes variant TSS, "Against Waiting"), 1962-1968 (Box 13:956)
    - Sirventes on a Sad Occurrence ( In Time), ca. 1962-1968 (Box 13:957)
    - Six Candles, 1962 (Box 13:958)
    - Six-Day and Ball-Bearing ( In Time), ca.1962 (Box 13:959)
    - Social Poem ( The Dutiful Son), 1953-1955 (Box 13:960)
    - Some Children, Kansas, One Night, Other Things, Anomalies ( On Occasion), 1968 (Box 13:961)
    - Some Questions for Today ( On Occasion), 1969 (Box 13:962)
    - Some Suggested Guidelines ("from DADDY") ( On Occasion), ca. 1968-1970 (Box 13:963)
    - So New I, ca. 1964-1968 (Box 13:964)
    - Song Before Bed ( The Love Bit), 1958 (Box 13:965)
    - Song for Two Voices ( On Occasion), 1965 (Box 13:966)
    - Song for a Happy Man ( The Love Bit), 1957 (Box 13:967)
    - Sonnet ( On Occasion) (includes MSS version), 1960-1970 (Box 13:968)
    - Speech ( In Time), 1962-1968 (Box 13:969)
    - Spring, ca. 1971-1980 (Box 13:970)
    - Spring ( Why Not), ca. 1983-1985 (Box 13:971)